In the last session, we looked at what it means to structure a message in a clear and compelling way.
And today we’re going to explore how to convert that structure into a storyline,
and then even take that storyline and tell a good story around it. Storylining and storytelling are actually two very different things.
So what do we mean by that? Storylining is actually converting your pyramid and your synthesis into a prose version.
Dot-dash is often what we use as well
to convey this. And so it’s actually an outline of the kind of key points you want to get across, and what order they might come in, and what would be the other supporting evidence to make your argument.
Storytelling, on the other hand, is a very different art.
That’s when you’re actually thinking about: how can I engage and hook my audience in a different way? How can I inspire them?
So while the structure of the ideas, the clarity of the message, is absolutely critical, the order in which the story is told is important.
Storytelling starts getting into more of those exciting angles and
ways of inspiring your audience. We will be joined by a host of great experts who will help you
learn how to do storylining well and to tell a good story.